

## **Curriculum Vitae for Eivind Storm Aarnæs**

#### Personal information

Address: Maridalsveien 240 E-mail: eivind@xal.no

0467 Oslo Phone: +47 988 84 317

Born: 21.02.1991 Nationality: Norwegian

# **Summary**

I have a masters degree in Computational Science from the University of Oslo, completed in 2016. My project was about a particle system modeling linear elasticity, and accelerating linear algebra computations using GPUs. From my studies leading to this degree I have gained broad knowledge about algorithms, numerical mathematics, and programming in several languages.

Work experience prior to Expert Analytics includes mostly one-to-one teaching in a lab setting, but also as lecturing and live coding in plenary settings. I have also worked with testing—both manual and automated, and with Android development and some minor Javascript development.

#### Technical skills

Languages C/C++, Python, Java, TeX/LaTeX

Frameworks OpenCL, Numpy and SciPy, Matplotlib, Boost.Python and Pybind11,

PyTest

Tools Sphinx, Git, CMake, Vim editor, JetBrains IDEs (PyCharm, IntelliJ,

and CLion), Docker

## **Education**

2011 – 2014 Bachelor Degree in Applied Mathematics at the University of Oslo.

2014 – 2016 Masters Degree in Computational Science at the University of Oslo.

My thesis was titled "Sparse Matrix Storage Schemes for a Linear

System arising from a Discrete Model of Elasticity".

## **Professional experience**

2017 – 2012 – 2015	Consultant at Expert Analytics AS.  Teaching Assistant at the University of Oslo in the course "INF1100: Introduction the programming with scientific applications". Only the autumn semesters.  Was responsible for a weekly programming lab. I also corrected as-
	signments for my class.
2013 – 2014	Summer intern and contract software developer at Teleplan Globe AS. Prototyped an Android app for logging mobile network parameters,
	and identifying all the cell towers the device communicated with.
2014 – 2014	Teaching Assistant at the University of Oslo in the course <i>"INF1010: Object oriented programming"</i> . Only the spring semester.
	Shared responsibility for both reviewing the past weeks exercises in plenary for the entire course, and lecturing the pre-course for students with no prior knowledge in Java.
2013 - 2013	Teaching Assistant at the University of Oslo in the course <i>"INF1010:</i>
	Object oriented programming". Only the spring semester.
	Was responsible for a weekly programming lab. I also corrected as-
2012 – 2013	signments for my class. Summer intern at Teleplan Globe AS.
2012 2010	Worked on testing web applications: both manually and by automating manual procedures.

## Languages

Norwegian Native proficiency

English Professional working proficiency

### Personal skills

Reading Code Through my work as a teaching assistant I have read and graded

> somewhere around 140 000 lines of code (Python/Java), and as a developer I have reviewed and provided feedback to both developers

and specialists.

Technology I have a large enthusiasm for learning and mastering anything within

programming, technology, and science.

Problem I enjoy working on and finding solutions to non-obvious problems, and solving

are able to see and work with strengths and weaknesses that may

appear.

# **Extended descriptions of selected projects**

Activity Domain and asset modelling at Arundo Analytics

Period Nov. 2019 — July 2020

Role Developer Staffing On my team: 2-3 developers and an architect, the entire project in-

cluded about 10 people

Volume 40% until Jan. 2020, 100% from Jan. 2020

Description I worked in a team with designing and implementing a domain and

asset model to be used in a project developing a cloud solution for

petrochemical plants.

I joined in the design and prototype phase of creating the model, and continued into developing the implementation to be used with the rest of the project. I worked on the overall model design in collaboration with the rest of the team, and on the data structure components of the model, and on parsing, analysing, and cleaning existing Json data

for before importing.

Tools Python, TypeScript, Git, JIRA, and Confluence

Activity Prototype IoT platform at Statkraft

Period July 2019 — Nov. 2019

Role Developer Staffing 3 developers

Volume 20%

Description At Statkraft they need to monitor and collect diverse sensor data. To

look into building their own IoT platform they are hosting a project to set up a prototype platform, and develop sensor nodes to collect

operational data from a wind park.

My role in the project is to design and build the sensor node, to implement communication between the node and the gateway using LoRaWAN, and interface the node with the sensor circuitry being

developed in parallel.

Tools ESP32, Arduino, ESP-IDF, and C/C++

Activity Data collection, modelling, and analysis at Statkraft

Period Aug. 2017 — Dec. 2019

Role Developer

Staffing 3 developers, 2 hydrologists

Volume 100% until June 2019, 80% from July 2019, 60% from November

2019

Description Statkraft is a major hydropower producer in Norway, and have need

of stable and correct data. As part of updating their data frameworks they are hosting several projects for improving data collection and

storage, and redesigning models and access layers.

My role has been to develop interfaces and collection utilities for unstable data sources, design and implement a model of the network of sensor stations and nodes, and data analysis of hydro-

logical/meterologial time series data.

Tools Python, C++, Boost Python, Git, and Sphinx

Activity The norwegian land register (NO: "Matrikkelen") at Kartverket

Period Apr. 2017 — May 2017

Role Developer

Staffing More than 10 developers

Volume 100%

Description Kartverket develops and maintains the land register software systems.

The system has to be performant for changes, and to keep a full history

of every change to the data.

I have redesigned and implemented the algorithms for computing chan-

ges to land borders using a specialized depth-first graph search.

Tools Java, Oracle SQL, Hibernate, IntelliJ IDEA, JIRA, Confluence, and

Perforce

Activity Region and Municipality reorganization (NO: "Kommunereformen")

at Kartverket

Period Jan. 2017 — Apr. 2017

Role Developer Staffing 5 developers Volume 100%

Description Kartverket develops and maintains the land register software systems.

As part of the norwegian region and municipality reoragnization, the land register needs to perform huge number of changes in as short a time as possible. As such they need to implement specialized algorithms to be able to process the data in the available time frame. My part of the project has been to develop algorithms to automatically partition land data into sets of independent structures to enable parallel processing without dead-locking the database. Data dependence was defined by both logical and algorithmic constraints of the data transforms, and by database constraints. The partitioning was done

using graph search and graph partitioning algorithms.

Tools Java, Oracle SQL, Hibernate, IntelliJ IDEA, JIRA, Confluence, and

Perforce

Activity A C++/OpenCL library for sparse linear algebra

Period Aug. 2015 — Dec. 2017 Role Researcher and developer

Staffing 1 researcher Volume 100%

Description Developed as part of my masters degree at the University of Oslo.

The library implements several different sparse matrix schemes and matrix-vector operations. Matrix-vector algorithms are implemented both serially, and parallel for GPUs using the OpenCL framework.

Tools C++, OpenCL, Python, CMake, and Git

Activity Prototype an Android app for logging mobile network parameters

Period June 2013 — Aug. 2014

Role Developer Staffing 1 developer

Volume June/July 2013 and 2014: 100%. Otherwise: 20%

Description

The project was to determine if an Android device coupled with proprietary data from the network operator could access enough parameters from the mobile network as to be usefull for logging network state and diagnosing network problems. To access enough parameters hidden Android APIs was accessed through reflection in addition to the public APIs available through the Android SDK. As the app used proprietary network data it was never meant for public use and is not available.

Tools

Android, Java, IntelliJ IDEA, Gradle, and Git